Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
Mama!
Mother. What are you...
I thought you were a burglar.
I didn't mean to
scare you. darling.
I was just getting a snack.
Go back to bed.
What's the matter?
Go on. back to bed.
I'll make you a hot chocolate.
Who are you?
And what have you
done with my mother?
My mother has never set
foot in this kitchen in her life.
And she certainly never
made me a hot chocolate.
Unless you count ordering
the maid to do it.
You're not scared of me?
I always believed I couldn't
be the only one in the world.
The only person who was
different.
And here you are.
Charles Xavier.
Raven.
You're hungry and alone.
Take whatever you want.
We've got lots of food.
You don't have to steal.
In fact.
you never have to steal again.
Understand this. Erik...
These Nazis. I'm not like them.
Genes are the key. yes?
But their goals?
Blue eyes? Blond hair? Pathetic.
Mmm!
Eat the chocolate.
It's good.
Want some?
I want to see my mama.
Genes are the key that unlocks
the door to a new age. Erik.
A new future for mankind.
Evolution.
You know what I'm talking about?
It's a simple thing I ask of you.
A little coin is nothing
compared to a big gate.
Is it?
Ja.
I tried. herr doctor.
I can't... I don't...
It's impossible.
The one thing I can
say for the Nazis
is their methods seem
to produce results.
I'm sorry. Erik.
Mama!
My darling.
How are you?
Here's what we're going to do.
I'm going to count to three...
And you're going to move the coin.
You don't move the coin.
I pull the trigger.
Understand?
One.
Mama.
You can do it.
Two.
Everything is all right.
Three.
Yes. Wonderful.
Excellent.
Nein!
Outstanding. Erik.
So we unlock your gift with anger.
Anger and pain.
You and me...
We're going to have a
lot of fun together.
Heterochromia.
A gentleman would at least
offer to buy me a drink first.
Norman. a pint of bitter for
me and a Brandy for the lady. please.
How did you know that?
Lucky guess.
My name is Xavier.
Charles Xavier.
How do you do? Amy.
Heterochromia was in
reference to your eyes.
which I have to say are stunning.
One green. one blue.
It's a mutation. It's a
very groovy mutation.
I've got news for you. Amy.
You are a mutant.
First you proposition a girl.
and then you call her deformed.
How is that seduction
technique working for you?
I'll tell you in the morning.
No. seriously.
though. you mustn't knock it.
Mutation took us from
single-celled organisms
to being the dominant form of
reproductive life on this planet.
Infinite forms of variation
with each generation.
all through mutation.
Then let's reclaim that word.
Mutant and proud.
Chin-chin. Hey.
I guess I have to buy my own drink.
I'm sorry. One cola.
Charles here was just telling me
that I'm like one of the first
sea creatures that grew legs.
A tiny bit sexier.
I'm sorry. This is
my sister. raven.
Hi. Amy.
And what do you study?
Waitressing.
Ah.
Oh. look. you have
heterochromia. too.
Sorry. what? Look at her eye.
Right. Raven. get
your coat. please.
Don't talk to me.
You did that on purpose.
I did not! Why would I do it
on purpose? Yes. you did!
You know I can't control it
sometimes if I'm stressed or tired.
You seem to be doing a
perfectly good job right now.
"Mutant and proud." What?
Or is it only with
pretty mutations.
or invisible ones like yours?
But if you're a freak.
you better hide.
You're being ridiculous.
I don't mean to sound
like an old fart.
Which you are.
Sometimes.
But we've talked about this. raven.
A small slip-up is one thing.
A big one does not
bear thinking about.
"Mutant and proud."
"Mutant and proud"?
If only.
Would you date me?
Of course I would.
Any young man would be lucky
to have you. You are stunning.
Looking like this?
Like... what?
Blue?
You're my oldest friend.
I'm your only friend.
Thank you for that.
Well?
I'm incapable of thinking
of you that way.
I feel responsible for you.
Anything else would
just feel wrong.
But what if you didn't know me?
Unfortunately. I do know you.
I don't know what's
gotten into you lately.
You're awfully concerned
with your looks.
I'm sleepy.
Will you read to me?
I can't. I have my thesis
coming up. I have to study.
Fine. read that. Your thesis
always sends me right off.
"To homo neanderthalensis. his
mutant cousin. homo sapiens."
"was an aberration."
"Peaceful cohabitation. if ever
it existed. was short-lived."
"Records show.
without exception."
"that the arrival of the mutated
human species in any region"
"was followed by the
immediate extinction"
"of their less-evolved kin."
Possession of that gold is illegal.
I should inform the police.
Let's not play this game.
Where did you get it?
A friend.
He recommended your
bank most highly.
I see.
Do you know our terms. sir?
Yes.
And you should know mine.
This gold is what
remains of my people.
Melted from their possessions.
Torn from their teeth.
This is blood money.
And you're going to help me find
the bastards responsible for it.
Don't touch that alarm.
I want schmidt. Klaus schmidt.
Where is he?
Our clients don't provide
addresses. We're not...
Not that sort of bank?
Metal fillings. eh?
Not gold.
Worried someone
might steal them?
Argentina! Schmidt
is in Argentina!
Villa gesell! Please!
Thank you.
I would love to kill you.
So mark my words.
If you warn anyone I'm coming...
I will find you.
Another day
at the office.
Is that
colonel hendry?
The NATO guy?
Yeah.
Yes. it is.
Because that's three mob
bosses. the Italian ambassador
and the ceo of lockheed.
They can't all be communists.
This hellfire club. it's
got to be something else.
Do you see that?
Hello. girls.
Wow! Very nice.
What are you doing?
Using some equipment the CIA
didn't give me. Stay put.
Colonel hendry? Yes. ma'am.
Emma frost. Sebastian
Shaw's associate.
And where is Mr. Shaw?
We're having a party. and
here's the entertainment.
Come with me.
Down like a roller coaster.
Back like a loop-the-loop.
And around like a
merry-go-round.
We ate and ate at
a hot dog stand.
We danced around to a rocking band.
And when I could. I
gave that girl a hug.
In the tunnel of love.
You'll never know how
great a kiss can feel.
When you stop at the
top of a Ferris wheel.
When I fell in love
down at palisades park.
Hello. beautiful. How are you?
Hey. baby. You want to
find a quiet place?
I am so sorry. I've been
booked by colonel hendry.
Excuse me.
We ate and ate at a hot dog stand.
We danced around
to a rocking band.
And when I could. I
gave that girl a hug.
In the tunnel of love.
You'll never know how
great a kiss can feel.
You sure we can't get
you a refill. Bob?
No.
So. I hear you blocked the proposal to
position Jupiter missiles in Turkey.
I expect you'll reconsider.
We've had this conversation.
You put our nukes in Turkey or
anywhere that close to Russia.
and you're looking at war.
Nuclear war.
I don't ask for favors. colonel.
I express my expectations.
So. let me say it again.
I expect you'll reconsider.
The only thing I will reconsider
is having another glass of
that delicious champagne.
What the hell did you
put in my drink?
You're thinking of running.
Hiding.
We'd find you. hendry.
There's not a fortress in the
world that could keep us out.
Magnificent. Isn't she. Bob?
Genetic mutation.
The evolution of the human genome.
Where's azazel?
Ah. We don't want the
colonel to be late.
Comrade.
Missiles in Turkey
send a very clear message.
If we ever decide to fire them.
the Russian early-warning system
won't even have time to kick in.
This better be
important. mactaggert.
Whoa. slow down.
Are you smoking them funny cigarettes?
People don't disappear.
Colonel hendry was there.
He was there. mccone.
in the hellfire club.
Colonel hendry?
I agree with you. general.
I've reconsidered my position
and I now believe we should put
Jupiter missiles in Turkey.
Colonel hendry is here.
So unless he magically traveled
3.000 Miles in the last 10 minutes.
listen to me. I suggest that
you stop wasting my time.
Looks like hendry wants
to start world war III.
I got bigger things to deal
with right now. mactaggert.
Sir. I...
God!
Have you lost your mind?
So. now what?
We find an expert on
genetic mutation.
PR ofessor of genetics.
Charles Francis Xavier.
So. how does it feel
to be a Professor?
Don't call me that. You don't
get to be called a Professor
until you actually have
a teaching position.
I know. but it suits you.
Don't say that. Do say.
"let's go have a drink."
Let's go have a drink.
Wonderful.
Afternoon. gentlemen.
Hot out there.
Beer. please.
German beer.
Of course.
Yes. it's bitburger.
You like it?
The best.
What brings you to Argentina?
The climate.
I'm a pig farmer.
Tailor.
Since I was a boy.
My father made the finest
suits in Dusseldorf.
My parents were from Dusseldorf.
Ah.
What was their name?
They didn't have a name.
It was taken away from them...
By pig farmers...
And tailors.
Blood and honor.
Which would you
care to shed first?
We were under orders...
Blood then.
Freeze. asshole.
Come on. shoot.
Who... what are you?
Let's just say I'm
Frankenstein's monster.
And I'm looking for my creator.
Drink! Drink! Drink!
Yeah!
I'm so proud of you. Thank you.
I need another drink. And
you need another cola.
Congratulations. Professor.
Thank you very much.
It's much harder than
it looks. actually.
No. on your presentation.
You were at my presentation? How
nice of you. Thank you very much.
Moira mactaggert.
Charles Xavier. Do
you have a minute?
For a pretty little bean
with a mutated mcrl gene?
I have five.
I say "MCRL." you would
say "AUBURN HAIR."
It's a mutation.
It's a very groovy mutation.
Mutation. right.
took us from single-celled
organisms to the dominant form...
You know what? This routine may
go over great with the co-eds.
but I'm here on business.
What?
I really need your help.
All right.
The kind of mutations that you
were talking about in your thesis.
I need to know if they may
have already happened.
In people alive today.
Professor?
I think we should just
talk when you're sober.
Do you have any time tomorrow?
Something tells me you already
know the answer to your question.
This is very important to me. and if
I can help you. I will do my utmost.
Thank you.
Still drinking champagne. Bob?
I will pass.
Okay. well. so much
for the pleasantries.
I was wondering who you told
about our little arrangement.
No one.
- He's telling the truth.
- Good.
Well. I guess we're done here.
Let's wrap things up. shall we?
Oh. I knew better
than to trust you.
Now. you let me walk out
of here with my money.
or I will pull this
pin. and we all die.
Go ahead. Pull it.
I'll do it. I swear to God.
No. you won't.
But I will.
You're one of them?
Very astute of you. colonel hendry.
You want to guess what I can do?
I've got the power to absorb energy.
It keeps me young.
But that's the boring part.
The fun stuff is what I can
do with it once I've got it.
The advent
of the nuclear age
may have accelerated
the mutation process.
Individuals with extraordinary
abilities may already be among us.
Thank you very much.
Mactaggert. you really think
that some crackpot scientist
is going to make me believe in
sparkly dames and vanishing men?
You just bought yourself a one-way
ticket back to the typing pool.
This meeting is over.
Please sit down. agent mactaggert.
I didn't really expect
you to believe me.
given that all you could think
about during my presentation was
what sort of pie they were
serving in the commissary.
It's apple pecan.
I haven't been entirely honest
with you. love. I'm sorry.
You see. one of the
many spectacular things
my mutation allows me to do
is that I can read your mind.
I've seen this before
in a magic show.
Are you going to ask us to think of
a number between one and 10 now?
No. agent stryker. Although.
I could ask you about
your son. William.
who you were thinking
about. which is very nice.
But I think I'd rather ask you
about the Jupiter missiles
America are currently
placing in Turkey.
He's a goddamn spy.
You brought a goddamned
spy into this facility!
How's that for a magic trick?
Best I've ever seen.
I want them out of here.
And locked down until I can
figure out what to do.
My facility is off-site.
I'll take them.
I can't believe this. You'd
think the director of the CIA
would have a little more composure.
We should be going
after Shaw right now.
But instead. he's out there
worrying about the wrong mutants.
What are we going to do. levene?
Levene?
Levene. what's wrong with you?
Absolutely nothing.
I've just frozen him for a moment
because I'd like to talk to you.
It's good. isn't it?
I'm as interested in this
Sebastian Shaw as you are.
If you still want my help. meet me on
the third floor of the parking garage.
I've always known that
there were people like you out there.
I've been the laughing stock of this
agency for years. but I knew it!
You are going to love my facility.
- That's going to have to wait.
- Why?
Agent mactaggert has a
lead on Sebastian Shaw.
and if we don't move now. apparently.
we're going to lose him.
What?
Not only can he read minds.
he can communicate
with them as well.
Moira and I have just had
a lovely conversation.
Yes. we did.
That is incredible!
But I cannot take you anywhere else
without permission from upstairs.
Like to see one more
magic trick? Okay.
Get in the car. Good idea.
Herr doktor.
Little Erik lensherr.
He's here to kill you.
What kind of a greeting is that...
After all these years?
Emma.
We don't harm our own kind.
Ah! Now it's a party.
This
is the us coast guard.
Do not attempt to move your
vessel. Stay where you are.
They have a telepath.
I've lost Shaw.
There's something blocking me.
This has never
happened to me before.
I think there's someone
like me on that ship.
Like you?
I'm sorry. a telepath.
This is incredible.
I could actually feel her
inside my mind. I'm very sorry.
but I don't think I'm gonna
be much help tonight.
You're on your own.
Oh. my God! Jesus!
Get inside.
Stop. stop. stop.
Charles!
Are you okay?
There's someone else out there.
There.
Time to go.
Let go!
You have to let it go!
You've got to put someone
in the water to help him.
Let it go!
You have to let it go!
You can't. You'll drown.
You have to let go.
I know what this means to
you. but you're going to die.
Please. Erik. calm your mind.
Get off me!
Get off!
Calm down! Just breathe.
We're here!
Who are you?
My name is Charles Xavier.
You were in my head.
How did you do that?
You have your tricks.
I have mine.
I'm like you.
Just calm your mind.
I thought I was alone.
You're not alone.
Erik. you're not alone.
Welcome to my facility.
My mission has been to investigate
the application of paranormal
powers in military defense.
Or offense.
This guy Shaw. schmidt.
whatever you want to call him.
he's working with the Russians.
We might need your help to stop him.
Marvelous.
So we're to be the CIA's
new mutant division. yes?
Something like that.
It's a supersonic.
The most advanced plane ever built.
You should see it in real life.
It's incredible.
Hank. these are the special new
recruits I was telling you about.
This is Hank McCoy. one of our
most talented young researchers.
How wonderful. Another
mutant. already here.
Why didn't you say?
Say what?
Because you don't know.
I am so. so terribly sorry.
Hank?
You didn't ask.
so I didn't tell.
So. your
mutation is what?
You're super-smart?
I'll say.
Hank here graduated
Harvard at the age of 15.
I wish that's all it was.
You're among friends now. Hank.
You can show off.
Splendid.
I'm sorry.
Ta-da!
You're amazing.
Really?
"The presence
of us missiles in Turkey"
"represents an
unprecedented threat"
"to the people of
the Soviet union."
warned Russian foreign minister
gromyko earlier today.
But he was quick to insist the
Russians would not be the first
to initiate any military action.
Yeah. we'll fix that as
soon as we get to Russia.
Unless the CIA find us first.
I'll take care of them. too.
If that telepath gets
inside your head.
he won't be as much fun as I am.
Already in hand. my love.
The Russians
made me this.
So. what am I thinking?
I don't know.
I was thinking that you are
the most exquisite thing
I have ever seen in my life.
And that this needs ice.
Fetch me some.
There's a good girl.
I promised myself I'd find a cure
ever since I was a little boy.
You have no idea what
I'd give to feel
normal. Normal.
Charles has never understood.
He's different. but
he's never had to hide.
Hank. this serum
that you're making.
it doesn't affect
abilities. right?
Just appearance.
It normalizes it.
Yeah.
Do you think it would work on me?
I can look into it. if you'd like.
It's the least I can do
after asking you to come down
here with such a weird request.
I have to admit. usually when guys ask
me out. they're not after my blood.
Sorry. I didn't intend
to be forward. I was just...
I was excited. You know. the
nature of your mutation.
If any genes hold the key to
changing appearance. it's yours.
Hank. you weren't being forward.
That's kind of what I meant.
No.
But I'm just sorry if
you thought I was.
And I'm sorry that you weren't.
Go ahead.
Take the blood.
Sorry.
Did I hurt you?
Kinky.
By the way. if I looked like you.
I wouldn't change a thing.
From what
I know about you.
I'm surprised you've
managed to stay this long.
What do you know about me?
Everything.
Then you know to
stay out of my head.
I'm sorry. Erik. but I've
seen what Shaw did to you.
I've felt your agony.
I can help you.
I don't need your help.
Don't kid yourself. You
needed my help last night.
It's not just me you're
walking away from.
Here you have the chance to be part of
something much bigger than yourself.
I won't stop you leaving.
I could.
But I won't.
Shaw has got friends.
You could do with some.
Hank turned that radar
installation into a transmitter.
It's designed to amplify brainwaves
so it could enhance
your telepathic powers.
help us find other mutants
for our division.
What if they don't want
to be found by you?
Erik.
You decided to stay.
If a new species is
being discovered.
it should be by it's own kind.
Charles and I find the mutants.
No suits.
First of all. that's
my machine out there.
Second of all. and much more
importantly. this is Charles' decision.
Charles is fine with the
CIA being involved.
Isn't that right?
No. I'm sorry. but
I'm with Erik.
We'll find them alone.
What if I say no?
Then good luck using your
installation without me.
I call it cerebro.
As in the Spanish for "brain." Yes.
Okay. so. the electrodes connect Charles
to the transmitter on the roof.
When he picks up a mutant. his brain
sends a signal through a relay
and then the co-ordinates of their
location are printed out here.
You designed this?
Yeah.
What an adorable lab
rat you make. Charles.
Don't spoil this for me. Erik.
I've been a lab rat. I
know one when I see one.
Okay. great. Are you sure
we can't shave your head?
Don't touch my hair. Okay.
It's working!
For that. daddy-o. you
get a private dance.
You cats know it's
double for both. right?
Mmm.
No. that won't be necessary.
Although. I'm sure it'd be magical.
We were thinking more.
we'll show you ours
if you show us yours.
Baby. that is not the way
it works around here.
More tea. vicar?
Don't mind if I do.
My turn.
How would you like a job where
you get to keep your clothes on?
Where to. fellas? Richmond.
Virginia. please.
Right. so. you want the airport?
The station? What?
No. we were rather hoping you
would take us all the way.
That's a six-hour drive.
That will give us
plenty of time to talk.
What does the government
want with a guy like Alex summers?
I hope you're not planning
on putting him with others.
First guy I've ever met who actually
prefers solitary confinement.
Crazy. huh?
What?
You like fish. I like fish. too.
Maybe we should get a bite
sometime. talk about it?
I'd rather go out with the fish.
These fish?
Excuse me. I'm Erik lensherr.
Charles Xavier.
Go fuck yourself.
There's nothing on radar?
Nothing.
Sonar?
Nyet.
Then we have a problem.
Beautiful. isn't it?
The reason we exist.
We are the children
of the atom. my love.
We have a situation.
The telepath.
I shouldn't be able to
feel him at this distance.
It's like his reach is
amplified.
They're recruiting.
You go on to Russia.
I'll handle them.
I can't stop thinking
about the others out there.
All those minds that I touched.
I could feel them.
Their isolation. their
hopes. their ambitions.
I tell you. we are at the start
of something incredible. Erik.
We can help them.
Can we?
Identification.
that's how it starts.
And ends with being rounded up.
experimented on. eliminated.
Not this time.
We have common enemies.
Shaw. the Russians.
They need us.
For now.
We should
think of code names.
We're government agents now. we
should have secret code names.
I want to be called mystique.
Damn! I wanted to
be called mystique.
Well. tough. I called it.
And I'm way more
mysterious than you.
Darwin. what about you?
Well. "Darwin" is
already a nickname.
and. you know. it sort of fits.
Adapt to survive and all.
Check this out.
Whoa!
That was incredible. Thank you.
What about you?
I'm going to be.
Banshee.
Why do you want to be named
after a wailing spirit?
You might want to cover your ears.
Your turn.
My stage name is angel.
It kind of fits. You can fly?
Uh-huh. And...
What's your name?
How about big foot?
You know what they say
about guys with big feet.
And yours are kind of small.
Okay. now.
Alex. what is your gift?
What can you do?
It's not...
I just can't do it. I
can't do it in here.
Why
don't you just do it out there?
Alex!
Alex! Alex!
That's the spirit!
Get down when I tell you.
"Get down
when I tell you."
Get back.
Get back!
Whatever.
We have intel that Shaw is meeting with
the Russian defense chief in moscow.
So go ahead. Say it.
I'm not here to say "I told you
so." You know why I'm here.
Yeah. yeah. yeah. Clearance
to bring along your mutants.
Fight fire with fire.
It makes sense.
Wait! You're okay with this?
Sending in a bunch of
untrained. unauthorized freaks?
These freaks are dedicated.
hardworking people.
Plane leaves for Russia in an hour.
I'm telling you. these kids
are not ready for Shaw.
I think they're gonna surprise you.
They're an exceptional
bunch of young people.
What the hell?
Come on! You can
go harder than that.
Harder!
What are you doing?
Who destroyed the statue?
It was Alex.
No. havok.
We have to call him havok.
That's his name now.
And we were thinking. you
should be Professor x
and you should be Magneto.
Exceptional.
I expect more from you.
We got a problem. What?
I'm so sorry. This
wasn't on the map.
No matter what
happens. act normally.
I'll take care of this. all right?
Now. listen to me...
- Where are you going?
- To our farm.
Open the back.
As you wish.
Easy. easy.
Take it easy. chaps.
- Anything back there?
- Nothing. It's empty.
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
- Where is Shaw?
- I don't know.
But if she's a telepath and I
read her. she'll know we're here.
Let me try something else.
Shaw sends his apologies
but he's indisposed.
He asked me to come in his place.
And between you and I. honey.
I'm a lot better company.
Please. come in.
He's not coming.
So. what now. boss?
Now. nothing. We're here
for Shaw. Mission aborted.
The hell it is. Erik.
She's his right-hand woman.
That's good enough for me.
The CIA invading the home of a senior
Soviet official. Are you crazy?
I'm not CIA.
Erik!
Your health.
So. you must be busy
planning your next move.
What with the Americans refusing to
remove their missiles from Turkey.
You know I can't talk about
those things. miss frost.
Emma.
And don't worry.
You don't have to say a word.
He's gonna start
world war III single-handed.
We have to do something.
Like what?
We're moving out.
You can't!
I'm sorry.
I can't leave him.
For God's sake. Erik!
Be calm.
Forget my face.
You are beautiful. so beautiful!
Yes!
Pathetic.
Nice trick.
Who are you?
Go to sleep.
You can stop trying to
read my mind. sugar.
You're never going to get anything
from me while I'm like this.
So. then. you can just tell us.
Where is Shaw?
Erik.
Erik. that's enough.
Erik. that's enough!
All yours.
She won't be shifting
into diamond form again.
And if she does. just
give her a gentle tap.
We are the
children of the atom.
Radiation gave birth to mutants.
What will kill the humans
will only make us stronger.
Beautiful. isn't it?
This is worse than we
previously imagined.
We're taking you with us.
CIA will want to
question you themselves.
Oh. I doubt it.
They have bigger things
to worry about right now.
- Whoa!
- All right. all right.
Jesus. man. you are killing me.
Don't beat yourself up. I've
had a lot of spare time.
Oh. I didn't know the
circus was in town.
Hey. come on. honey. Give us a little...
No?
Come on. let's see the foot.
There it is. Come on.
big foot. let's go.
Hey. Hey. come on. Hey.
They're just guys being stupid.
Guys being stupid. I can handle.
Okay?
I've handled that my whole life.
But I'd rather a bunch of guys
stare at me with my clothes off
than the way these
ones stare at me.
At us.
What was that?
I don't know.
Something doesn't feel right.
No news of Shaw?
Not a peep. Not even
through that back channel?
What is that?
We have an intruder
in the main atrium.
Where are the mutants?
If you take another step.
I'm gonna put you down.
Of course you will. But where do
I find the more evolved people?
Send back-up now!
Get back! Do not leave that
room. We're under attack!
Shoot! Shoot!
Where are the mutants?
Put that man down
or we will open fire!
Stay here. my ass! Let's go!
Get back! We can help!
We can help!
Wait!
You want the mutants? They're
right through that door.
Just let us normal people go.
We're no threat...
- Where is the telepath?
- Not here.
Too bad.
Well. at least I can take
this silly thing off.
Good evening.
My name is Sebastian Shaw.
And I am not here to hurt you.
Freeze!
Azazel.
My friends. there is
a revolution coming.
When mankind discovers who
we are. what we can do.
each of us will face a choice.
Be enslaved
or rise up to rule.
Choose freely. but know that
if you are not with us.
then. by definition. you are
against us.
So. you can stay
and fight for the people
who hate and fear you.
and queens.
Angel. Are you kidding me?
Come on.
We don't belong here.
And that's nothing
to be ashamed of.
We have to do something.
Stop.
I'm coming with you.
Good choice.
So. tell me about your mutation.
Well. I adapt to survive.
So. I guess I'm coming with you.
I like that.
Alex! Get out!
Do it!
Protecting your fellow mutants?
That's a noble gesture.
Feels good.
Adapt to this.
Hello.
Once again. my sympathies for your
treatment at the hands of the CIA.
These Americans are ruthless.
Now they have their missiles
placed in Turkey...
I expect you'll be planning new
missile sites of your own.
Somewhere you know the American
early-warning system won't help.
I hear Cuba is lovely
this time of year.
And so close to Florida.
Missiles in Cuba?
You're serious?
We may as well declare war.
Maybe I wasn't clear enough.
You will make this happen.
Okay.
Let's see
what kgb think about this.
Hello?
General armivolkoff.
It's nothing.
Raven?
We've made arrangements for you
to be taken home immediately.
We're not going home.
What?
He's not going back to prison.
He killed Darwin.
All the more reason
for you to leave.
This is over.
Darwin's dead. Charles.
And we can't even bury him.
We can avenge him.
Erik. a word. please.
They're just kids.
No. They were kids.
Shaw has his army. we need ours.
We'll have to train.
All of us.
Yes? Yeah.
Well. we can't stay here.
Even if they reopen the
department. it's not safe.
We've got nowhere to go.
Yes. we do.
The law says we've
got to turn her over.
The law applies
to human beings.
The same laws don't apply to
mutants. They're too dangerous.
In times like this. security is
more important than liberty.
There is a war coming. John.
Yes.
but a war with who?
Excellent question.
Though I wouldn't call
it a war. exactly.
That suggests both sides stand
an equal chance of winning.
Captain. no sign of
any American ships.
Maintain course. full ahead.
The Russians have
sent their warheads to Cuba.
We have a week before the
ship hits the coast.
Our fleet can be on this line when
the Russian missile ship arrives.
If that ship crosses the line.
they will have declared war
against the United States.
And we will have no choice but to
retaliate with a full nuclear response.
Do we agree?
Dispatch the 7th fleet.
This is yours?
No. it's ours.
Honestly. Charles. I don't know how you
survived. living in such hardship.
Well. it was a hardship
softened by me.
Come on. Time for the tour.
Dear comrades...
The United States have
dispatched warships for Cuba.
This leaves us with no choice.
Comrade first secretary...
We must send in our fleet.
Dispatch the fleet!
President Kennedy
has signed a formal proclamation
setting up a blockade of all
missiles bound for Cuba.
The Soviet
union reacted by terming it.
"A step along the road to
unleashing a thermo-nuclear war."
You're sure?
I'm sure.
All right.
No. No. I can't. I'm sorry.
I can't shoot anybody point
blank. let alone my friend.
Oh. come on. You know
I can deflect it.
You're always telling me
I should push myself.
If you know you can deflect it.
then you're not
challenging yourself.
Whatever happened to the man who
was trying to raise a submarine?
I can't. Something that big?
I need the situation. the anger...
No. the anger is not enough.
It's gotten the job
done all this time.
It's nearly gotten you
killed all this time.
Come here.
Let's try something a
little more challenging.
My stepfather took the possibility of
nuclear war quite seriously. This way.
That is why he had this
bunker built down here.
I thought we could use it as
a practice range of sorts.
You don't think I'm going
to blow through the walls?
He had this place built
to withstand a nuclear bomb.
I think it can handle you. Alex.
You know. when I do this.
bad things tend to happen.
That's because you can't
control it. It controls you.
That's why we're here. Alex.
It's why we're training.
What you're doing is incredible.
You're hitting a pitch
with sound waves
that have the same resonant frequency
as the glass. That's why it shatters.
But this. it's like any
other muscle in the body.
You can control it.
"In each of us. two
natures are at war."
Robert Louis Stevenson.
Jekyll and Hyde.
Top marks.
The story wasn't really about
good and evil though. was it?
It was about man's animal nature
and his struggle to
control it. to conform.
And it's that struggle
which is holding you back.
No. Jekyll was afraid of
what he could be capable of.
And you are. too.
If you're serious about me doing
this. you might want to get back.
All right.
Shall I shut the door? Yeah.
Whenever you're ready.
Oh. my God!
I will teach you to
control this. Alex.
And you're sure that
this will work?
Anything is possible.
I based the design...
Hank. stop talking. Come on.
Now. remember. Scream
as hard as you can.
You need the sound waves
to be supersonic.
Catch them at the right angle
and they should carry you.
They should carry me.
That's reassuring. Good luck.
And don't forget to scream.
Now. if you want to
beat me this time.
you have to set the beast free.
On your marks.
get set.
go!
Congratulations. my friend.
Robert Louis Stevenson
would have been proud.
Impressive. Hank.
With feet like those. all
you need is a red nose.
Right. bozo?
I'm done here. Thank you. Alex.
Come on. Hank.
If you're using half your
concentration to look normal.
then you're only half paying attention
to whatever else you're doing.
Just pointing out something
that could save your life.
You want society to accept you.
but you can't even accept yourself.
Sexy!
Well. this is just the prototype.
The real one will look
considerably better.
It will be a whole suit. See. these
sensors measure your energy output.
This panel focuses it and
the excess is absorbed.
Try hitting the one in the middle.
Just the one in the middle. mind.
Good luck.
You got to see this. Your genes
are extraordinary. you know that?
Your cells age at half the
rate of a normal human.
When you're 40. you'll still have
the leucocytes of a teenager.
You have the most incredible
cellular structure I've ever seen.
And you truly
believe I'll fly this time?
Unreservedly.
I trust you. I'm touched.
I don't trust him.
Say nothing.
I'm gonna die!
Look. we're not going to make you
do anything you don't feel...
Here. let me help.
Erik!
What?
You know you were
thinking the same.
Wonderful work. Hank.
Thank you very much.
All right. Alex. I want
you to hit the "X".
And try not to hit me.
There's a good chap.
You're serious?
I'm very serious.
I have complete and
utter faith in you.
Am I still a bozo?
Yes. Hank. you're still a bozo.
But nice job.
See that?
Try turning it to face us.
You know. I believe that true focus lies
somewhere between rage and serenity.
Would you mind if I...
What did you just do to me?
I accessed the brightest
corner of your memory system.
It's a very beautiful
memory. Erik. Thank you.
I didn't know I still had that.
There is so much more
to you than you know.
Not just pain and anger.
There is good. too.
I felt it.
When you can access all of that.
you'll possess a power
no one can match.
Not even me.
So. come on. Try again.
Hey! Well done.
The president is about
to make his address.
It shall be the policy of
this nation to regard any nuclear missile
crossing the embargo
line that surrounds Cuba
as an attack by the Soviet
union on the United States
requiring a full retaliatory
response upon the Soviet union...
That's where we're
going to find Shaw.
How do you know?
Two superpowers facing off and
he wants to start world war III.
He won't leave anything to chance.
So much for diplomacy.
I suggest you all get
a good night's sleep.
Ultimately
leads to war.
Tensions mount as the
Soviet missile ship nears Cuba.
All diplomatic efforts to avert
nuclear war have thus far failed.
As the American people
ready themselves
for the likelihood
of an atomic attack.
there are widespread
reports of panic-buying.
supermarkets cleared. as shelters
unused since the second world war
are stocked for what may lie ahead.
In all it's history. America has
never faced a greater threat.
The world is primed for war
and there's no one to stop me.
Come in.
Hey.
I have a surprise for you.
I isolated the right
marker in your DNA sample.
The serum works like an antibiotic.
attacking the cells that
'cause our physical mutation.
It won't affect our abilities.
just our appearance.
Do you still want to do this?
Should we have to hide?
Well. you already do.
You're hiding right now.
like I have my whole life.
I don't want to feel like a freak all
the time. I just want to look...
Normal. Yeah.
Hank. don't!
You're beautiful. Hank.
Everything you are.
you are perfect.
Look at all of us. Look at all
we've achieved this week.
All we will achieve.
We are different.
But we shouldn't be trying
to fit into society.
Society should aspire
to be more like us.
Mutant and proud.
It behooves me to tell you
that even if we save
the world tomorrow.
and mutants are
accepted into society.
my feet and your natural blue form
will never be deemed beautiful.
You look beautiful now.
We need this cure.
Cuba.
Russia. America.
It makes no difference.
Shaw has declared war on
mankind. on all of us.
He has to be stopped.
I'm not going to stop Shaw.
I'm going to kill him.
Do you have it in
you to allow that?
You've known all along
why I was here. Charles.
But things have changed.
What started as a covert mission.
tomorrow. mankind will
know that mutants exist.
Shaw. us. they won't differentiate.
They'll fear us.
And that fear will turn to hatred.
Not if we stop a war.
Not if we can prevent Shaw.
Not if we risk our lives doing so.
Would they do the same for us?
We have it in us to
be the better men.
We already are.
We're the next stage
of human evolution.
You said it yourself! No...
Are you really so naive
as to think that they won't
battle their own extinction?
Or is it arrogance?
I'm sorry?
After tomorrow. they're
going to turn on us.
But you're blind to it. because you
believe they're all like moira.
And you believe they're
all like Shaw.
Listen to me very
carefully. my friend.
Killing Shaw will not
bring you peace.
Peace was never an option.
No.
No. no. No.
Well.
this is a surprise.
The nice kind?
Get out. raven. I
want to go to bed.
Maybe in a few years.
How about now?
I prefer the real raven.
I said the real raven.
Perfection.
Could you pass me my robe?
You don't have to hide.
Have you ever looked at a tiger
and thought you ought
to cover it up?
No. but...
You're an exquisite
creature. raven.
All your life. the world
has tried to tame you.
It's time for you to be free.
You know. sometimes I wonder
what my life would have been like
if you hadn't found
me here that night.
Sorry. what? You...
For God's sake. raven!
Where are your clothes?
Put some clothes on.
That's not what you said
when you first saw me.
But I guess pets are always cuter
when they're little. right?
Raven. I don't know what's
gotten into you lately.
I thought you'd be in a good mood.
Hank. he tells me that he's found the
answer to your cosmetic problem.
Are you gonna tell
me what's the matter
or do I have to read your mind?
You promised me you
would never do that.
Until recently.
I never had to use my power to know
what you were thinking. raven.
Charles. I used to think it was going
to be you and me against the world.
But no matter how
bad the world gets.
you don't want to be
against it. do you?
You want to be a part of it.
What the hell happened here?
Hank has been busy.
Do we really have to wear these?
As none of us mutated to
endure extreme g-force
or being riddled by bullets.
I suggest we suit up.
Where is Hank?
I'm here.
Hank?
It didn't attack the cells.
It enhanced them.
It didn't work.
Yes. it did. Hank.
Don't you see?
This is who you were meant to be.
This is you.
No more hiding.
You never looked better. man.
Hank!
Don't mock me!
Hank. put him
down immediately. please.
Hank! Hank!
I wasn't.
Even I got to admit you
look pretty badass.
I think I got a new name for you.
Beast.
You're sure you can fly this thing?
Of course I can. I designed it.
Status of
the cargo ship.
Bearing
1-8-0 at 12 knots.
Three minutes to the
embargo line. sir.
God help them if they cross it.
God help us all.
Sound general quarters.
General quarters. general quarters!
- All hands. man battle stations!
- Aye. sir.
Set condition zebra!
General
quarters. battle stations.
Captain. we already have our
orders. Why so eager for new ones?
I lived through one war. comrade.
I'd prefer not to start another.
Battle stations! Now!
Gun boss. target cargo
ship bearing 1-8-0.
Fleet reports all weapons ready.
From the kremlin. sir.
New orders. As of 1025 hours. the cargo
vessel aral sea is hereby ordered to...
Reverse course and return
to port in Odessa.
Aral sea. come in.
They are not responding.
She's not turning around.
Aral sea. you are
ordered to turn around.
Do not cross the line.
Target ready to be fired upon. sir.
Stand by to fire. Standing by. sir.
Whoa!
It looks pretty messy out there.
Aral sea you are ordered
to turn around.
The crew of the aral sea are
all dead. Shaw's been there.
He's still here. somewhere.
He set the ship on course
for the embargo line.
If that ship crosses the line.
our boys are going to blow it up.
And the war begins.
Unless they're not our boys.
USS independence. this
is Alexander nevsky.
We have lost control
of our cargo ship.
She has been instructed to stop.
Do not fire! Repeat.
do not fire!
They have signaled the cargo
ship to turn around. sir.
It's a ruse. Pay no attention!
Stand by to fire.
Standing by to fire. sir.
On my count. Five.
four...
Hold on!
Nyet.
What was that? The Russians.
They have fired on
their own ship.
A little warning next
time. Professor.
Sorry about that. You all right?
Yeah.
Son of a...
Give me cinclant on the horn.
I want a new set of orders.
Congratulations. comrade.
You just averted nuclear war!
What?
Take him to the brig.
What just happened?
They say the comrade lost his mind.
The Americans are applauding.
They're here. That
telepath is powerful.
We're moving to a back-up plan.
That was inspired. Charles.
Thank you very much. but I
still can't locate Shaw.
He's down there. We
need to find him now.
Hank?
Is there anything unusual
on the radar or scanners?
No. Nothing.
Well. then he must be underwater.
And obviously. we don't have sonar.
Yes. we do. Yes. we do.
They are ready for war.
We just need to strike another
match to light the fuse.
And we still have the most
powerful weapon of all.
Me.
Turn the nuclear reactor to 100% output
and make sure I'm not disturbed.
Hank. level the bloody plane!
Whoa! You back right off.
Beast. open the bomb bay doors!
Remember! This is a muscle.
You control it!
You'll be in here
the entire time!
We'll see you soon!
On my mark! Three! Two!
One! Go!
Alert the fleet. they may
want to take their cans off.
Banshee has got a
location on Shaw.
Are you ready for this?
Let's find out.
Remember. the
point between rage
and serenity.
Erik. take my hand!
Oh.
Hold on. guys. It's
gonna get bumpy.
Erik. take my hand!
Moira? Moira. are you all right?
Yeah. I'm okay.
I read the teleporter's mind.
Shaw is drawing all the
power out of his sub.
He's turning himself into
some kind of nuclear bomb.
We got no time. The geiger
count is going out of control.
Moira. this is what
we're gonna do.
Get on the radio and tell them to
clear both fleets out immediately.
I'm going in. Beast.
havok. back him up.
Erik. I can guide you
through once you're in.
but I need you to shut down
whatever it is that's blocking me.
then we just hope to God it's not
too late for me to stop him.
Got it. Good luck!
Raven. stop! I'm
going to help them.
We don't have time for this.
If anything comes in that entrance.
you're taking care of it. yes?
Fine.
Beast!
If we go. you go!
We believe Shaw is trying to
detonate some kind of bomb.
Erik. make for the
middle of the vessel.
That's the point my
mind can't penetrate.
We have to assume that
that's where Shaw is.
Gangway! Gangway! Gangway!
That's the nuclear reactor.
Disable it.
Stop! Don't move!
Get down!
Erik. you're there.
You've reached the void.
He's not here. Charles. Shaw's
not here! He's left the sub!
What? He's got to be there.
He has to be!
There's nowhere else he can be.
Keep looking.
And I'm telling you he's not.
There's no one here. God damn it!
Erik.
What a pleasant surprise.
Erik? Erik.
So good to see you again.
May I ask you something?
Why are you on their side?
He's gone. What?
He's gone into the void! I can't
communicate with him there.
Why fight for a doomed
race who will hunt us down
as soon as they realize their
reign is coming to an end?
Yeah! Yes!
I'm sorry for what
happened in the camps.
I truly am.
He's back! Erik. whatever
you're doing. keep doing it.
It's starting to work.
But everything I
did. I did for you.
To unlock your power.
to make you embrace it.
It's working!
I'm starting to see him. but
I can't yet touch his mind.
You've come a long way
from bending gates.
I'm so proud of you.
And you're just starting
to scratch the surface.
Think how much further we could go
together.
Look out!
Stop! Azazel.
I don't want to hurt you. Erik.
I never did.
I want to help you.
This is our time.
Our age.
We are the future
of the human race.
You and me. son.
This world could be ours.
Everything you did
made me stronger.
It made me the weapon I am today.
It's the truth.
I've known it all along.
You are my creator.
Now. Charles!
Are you okay? Moira. be quiet.
I can only control
this man for so long.
- Sorry. Charles.
- Erik. please.
Be the better man.
It's not that I don't trust you.
Erik. there will be
no turning back!
No!
Charles!
Don't do this. Erik!
If you're in there.
I'd like you to know that I
agree with every word you said.
We are the future.
But.
unfortunately.
you killed my mother.
This is what we're going to do.
No. Please. Erik. no.
I'm going to count to three and
I'm going to move the coin.
One.
Please. Erik.
Two.
Three.
The Russians
share our concerns
and will join a strike
on all the mutants.
We can end this threat for good.
We'll never have another
opportunity like this.
We have an agent on that beach.
One agent.
She's a good agent.
She's collateral damage.
Today. our fighting stops!
Take off your blinders.
brothers and sisters.
The real enemy is out there.
I feel their guns
moving in the water.
their metal targeting us.
Americans. Soviets.
humans.
United in their fear
of the unknown.
The neanderthal is running
scared. my fellow mutants!
Go ahead. Charles.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Fleet commander. this
is X-ray bravo 7-0.
Respond. Over.
The beach is secure.
Call off the attack.
The beach is targeted and
ready to be fired upon. sir.
Stand by. Standing by. sir.
New orders. Fire on the beach.
Hello?
Hello!
Fire!
Erik. you said yourself.
we're the better men.
This is the time to prove it.
There are thousands of
men on those ships.
Good. honest. innocent men!
They're just following orders.
I've been at the mercy of
men just following orders.
Never again.
Erik. release them!
No!
I don't want to hurt you.
Don't make me!
Stand back!
Charles. that's enough!
Erik. stop!
Gentlemen. it's been an
honor serving with you.
Comrades. thank you
for your service.
I'm so sorry.
I said back off!
You. You did this.
Erik. Please.
She didn't do this. Erik.
You did.
Us turning on each other.
it's what they want.
I tried to warn you. Charles.
I want you by my side.
We're brothers. you and I.
All of us together.
protecting each other.
We want the same thing.
My friend.
I'm sorry. but we do not.
Charles! I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
It's all right.
This society won't accept us.
We form our own.
The humans have played their hand.
Now we get ready to play ours.
Who's with me?
No more hiding.
You should go with him.
It's what you want.
You promised me you would
never read my mind.
I know.
I promised you a great
many things. I'm afraid.
I'm sorry.
Take care of him.
And. beast. never forget.
Mutant and proud.
Help
me out. come on.
I'm gonna get you to a hospital.
Wait. Charles.
Charles. don't move. okay?
I won't.
Actually...
I can't feel my legs.
What? I can't feel my legs.
In this
week of Thanksgiving
there is much for which
we can be grateful
as we look back to where we
stood only four weeks ago.
The unity of this hemisphere.
the support of our allies
and the calm determination
of the American people.
These qualities may be tested
many more times in this decade.
So. how many students
do you think you'll have here
once you get the academy
up and running?
As many as I can manage.
Possibly more.
You know.
one day the government
is going to realize
how lucky they were to have
Professor x on their side.
I suppose I am a real
Professor now. aren't I?
Next thing you know.
I'll be going bald.
We're still on the
government's side. moira.
We're still g-men.
Just without the "g".
No. You're your own team now.
It's better.
You're X-Men.
Yes. I like the sound of that.
Moira?
For us. anonymity will be
the first line of defense.
I know.
They can threaten me all
they want. Charles.
I'll never tell them where you are.
Ever.
I know you won't.
I know.
I remember the attack on hq.
leaving to go somewhere else.
And then this morning.
I woke up at home.
That's it.
All that time. wiped clean
from your mind. Just gone.
He can do that? You don't
remember anything?
Sometimes I get fragments.
Like
trees.
sunlight.
A kiss.
Oh. Jesus.
Gentlemen. this is why the
CIA is no place for a woman.
What the hell was that?
I know we've had our differences.
Where's your telepath friend?
Gone.
Left a bit of a gap in my
life. if I'm to be honest.
I was rather hoping
you would fill it.
Join us.
Erik. I believe.
I prefer
Magneto.
-== [ www.OpenSubtitles.org ] ==-